Lloyd Lózes Goff Papers
Lloyd Lózes Goff Papers
1905-1971
Goff, Lloyd Lózes, 1917-1983.
2.25 linear ft.
Papers of the American painter, muralist, author and illustrator of children's books. Born 1917 in Texas. Includes correspondence (1934-1971); original artwork, including pastel drawings (1924-1937), illustrations for bookplates, book illustrations, and sketchbooks; reproductions and photographs of Goff's work (1932-1969); and memorabilia, including clippings (1930-1970), exhibition catalogs and announcements for one-man and group shows (1935-1971), and photographs (1905-1967) of Goff, his family, and friends.
149474
Biographical History
Lloyd Lózes Goff (1917- 1983) was an American muralist, graphic artist, author and illustrator of children's books. Born in Dallas, Texas, Goff studied at the Art Students League in New York and the University of New Mexico, where he later was Assistant Professor of Art (1943-1945).
Goff spent most of his career in the American Southwest, dividing his time between his home and studio in Albuquerque, New Mexico and a second studio in New York City, and much of his subject matter relates to the American west. He traveled extensively throughout the southwestern United States and Mexico, painting subjects from the Yucatan to Chihuahua, and his interest in hot-air ballooning produced two exhibitions of balloon subjects in the United States. He was a member of the Art Students League and the "Dallas Nine," and like many of his contemporaries participated in the WPA/Federal Arts Project in the 1930s.
In addition to his art and teaching work, Goff wrote or illustrated several books for children: Run, Sandpiper, Run (Goff, 1958), Fly Redwing Fly (Goff, 1959), That Girl of Pierre's (Davis, 1948), The Black Racer (MacKinnon, 1958). He also provided illustrations for several art books including Sun in Your Eyes: A New Light on The Southwest (Oren, 1948) and New Mexico Village Arts (Dickey, 1970).
Exhibits of Goff's work have appeared at the Art Institute of Chicago, Carnegie Institute, National Academy of Design, Pennsylvania Academy, San Francisco Art Association, and Whitney Museum of American Art as well as at least one show in London. His work is in the permanent collections of museums across the American Southwest including the Albuquerque Museum, Museum of Fine Arts-Santa Fe, Dallas Museum of Art, Panhandle-Plains Historical Museum, and Roswell Museum and Art Center, as well as in the Smithsonian American Art Museum and the Whitney Museum of American Art. His works can be seen at the Federal Buildings in Cooper, TX, and Hollis, OK, as well as the U.S. Treasury, New York City Municipal Building, Southern Methodist University in Dallas, the U.S. Customs House in New York City, and the U.S. Embassy in Ottawa, Canada.
[Portions of this biographical sketch adapted from article on Goff in Who Was Who in American Art, Sound View Press, 1985.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Spanning 1905 to 1971, the Lloyd Lózes Goff Papers comprises Biographical material, a Correspondence-subject file, Artwork, Writings, and Memorabilia. Focusing on the years 1950 through 1970, the collection illuminates both Goff's personal life and professional career.
Arranged alphabetically, the Correspondence-subject file (Boxes 1-2) consists of a number of incoming letters (1934-1971) from fellow artists (Edmund Minor Archer, Forrest Clemenger Bess, Isabel Bishop, Peter Blume, Paul Cadmus, Jared French, Raymond Jonson, John Koch, Edward Laning, Jack Levine, Robert Morse, Betty Parsons, Henry Schnakenberg, Ou Mie Shu, Katherine Schmidt Shubert, Theodoros Stamos, Stuyvesant Van Veen). Other correspondents include actresses (Lucille Ball, Edith Meiser, Vivian Vance, Nancy Wickwire); dancers (Frederic Franklin, Martha Graham); musicians/composers (James Galloway, Hugh Martin, Virgil Thompson); authors and editors (Margaret Anderson, Edwin Gilbert, David Greenhood, Anne Parrish, Fritz Peters, Glenway Wescott); as well as religious philosophers (Joseph Hubertus Pilates, Ervin Seale) and patrons (John Baragrey, Livia Gollancz, Judith H. Winans). The correspondence-subject file also reveals Goff's associations with art dealers, galleries, and museums (Beaufort Museum, Birmingham Museum of Art, Carnegie Institute, Cincinnati Art Museum, Custom Interiors, Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, Dayton Art Institute, Downtown Gallery, Galeria de Arte Mexicano, Museum of Fine Arts of Houston, Juster Gallery, Kerlan Collection of the University of Minnesota, C.W. Kraushaar Art Galleries, Maron Palais Galleries, National Academy of Design, La Quinta Gallery, Roko Gallery, Sixtieth Street Gallery, Springfield Art Museum, Wadsworth Atheneum, West Point Museum, Whitney Museum of American Art); cultural organizations (American Federation of Arts, Instituto Anglo-Mexicano de Cultura, Instituto Mexicano Norteamericano de Relaciones Culturales, Instituto Nacional de Bellas Artes); educational institutions (American Farm School, Art Students League of New York, Beaux Arts Institute of Design, Eureka College); libraries (Albuquerque Public Library, Library of Congress, New York Public Library); professional organizations (National Institute of Arts and Letters); and governmental agencies (City of Albuquerque, Penitentiary of New Mexico, the Bureau of Reclamation of the U.S. Department of the Interior, U.S. Office for Emergency Management, U.S. Post Office, U.S. Public Buildings Administration, and the U.S. Treasury Department). Notable among the undifferentiated correspondence are letters from children pertaining to Goff's artwork and children's books.
Artwork (Boxes 3-4) encompasses bookplates for the Albuquerque Public Library, illustrations for various books written and/or illustrated by Goff, a partial inventory of paintings, early drawings and paintings, one oil on canvas, pastel drawings, photographs and reproductions of paintings, and four sketchbooks. The bulk of this series consists of pastel drawings (1924-1937) and photographs of paintings (1932-1969) arranged chronologically by dates provided by Goff. Reproductions of Goff's paintings were incorporated in advertising promotions such as album covers of singer Gisele McKinsie, an issue of Ladies' Home Journal regarding interior decorating, and a brochure for model apartments entitled "The Lively Art of Living: Skyview on the Hudson." Sketchbooks bear dates 1925, 1928, 1932, and 1937, however their contents may extend beyond these years.
Writings (Box 4) consists of one poem and one speech. Memorabilia (Boxes 4-5) includes an exhibition list, photographs of Lloyd Lózes Goff (1935-1967), his family (1905-1959), and friends (1939-1960), printed material, awards, identification cards, invitations, permits, receipts, and personal documents. Printed material contains articles, reviews, clippings (1929-1971), exhibition catalogs of one-man (1939-1971) and group shows (1935-1968), theatre programs of the Albuquerque Little Theatre for which Goff's paintings were used in sets, and publicity for various books illustrated and/or written by Goff.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Art -- Illustrators; Literature -- Children's; Anderson, Margaret C.; Ball, Lucille, 1911-1989.; Baragrey, John, d. 1975.; Bess, Forrest Clemenger.; Bishop, Isabel, 1902-1988.; Blume, Peter, 1906-1992.; Blumenthal, Joseph, 1897-1990.; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.; Cadmus, Paul, 1904-1999.; Fergusson, Erna, 1888-1964.; Franklin, Frederic, 1914-; French, Jared, 1905-1988.; Galloway, James.; Gilbert, Edwin.; Goff, Lloyd Lózes, 1917-1983.; Graham, Martha.; Greenhood, David.; Jackson, Charles.; Jonson, Raymond, 1891-1982.; Kluckhohn, Clyde, 1905-1960.; Koch, John, 1909-; Laning, Edward, 1906-; Levine, Jack, 1915-; Martin, Hugh, 1914-; Parsons, Betty.; Peters, Fritz, 1913-1979.; Pilates, Joseph Hubertus.; Ruggles, Carl, 1876-1971.; Schnakenberg, Henry Ernest, 1892-; Shu, Ou Mie.; Shubert, Katherine Schmidt, 1898-1978.; Souza, Amilcar de.; Stamos, Theodoros, 1922-1997.; Thatcher, Madelaine.; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989.; Vance, Vivian.; Wescott, Glenway, 1901-1987.; Wickwire, Nancy.; Wyndham, Lee.; Albuquerque Public Library (N.M.); Treasury Relief Art Project.; United States. -- Public Buildings Administration.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Illustrators -- United States.; Mural painting and decoration -- United States -- 20th century.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Pastel drawing -- 20th century -- United States.; Portrait painters -- 20th century -- United States.; Bookplates.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Drawings (visual works); Exhibition catalogs.; Pastels.; Photographs.; Sketchbooks.; Artists.; Illustrators.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Lloyd Lózes Goff, 1970-71.
Inventory
- Biographical/autobiographical material
  - Biographical/autobiographical material (Box 1)
- Correspondence-subject file
  - Family correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - A-Z, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - City of Albuquerque, 1965 Aug. 23; 1965 Aug. 25 (Box 1)
  - Albuquerque Public Library, 1963 Jan. 9; 1963 Dec. 3,; 1965 May 13,; 1965 Nov. 1,; undated (printed material); includes (Box 1)
  - American Farm School, 1959 July (printed material); 1961 (printed material),; 1963 Feb. 14,; 1963 May 28,; undated (photographs) (Box 1)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1944 Apr. 15 (Box 1)
  - Amor, Ines, See Galeria de Arte Mexicano
  - Anderson, Margaret C., 1965 Apr. 13; 1965 Apr. 26,; 1965 Nov. 13,; 1966 Mar. 8,; 1966 Mar. 11,; 1966 Apr. 5,; 1966 Apr. 6,; 1966 Apr. 22,; 1966 July 29,; 1966 Sept. 20,; 1966 Nov. 25,; 1966 Dec. 10,; 1967 Jan. 27,; 1967 Mar. 31,; 1967 May 2,; 1967 July 14,; 1968 Feb. 20,; 1968 Aug. 17,; 1969 Oct. 17,; 1970 June 10,; undated (Box 1)
  - Archer, Edmund Minor, 1970 Feb. 4; 1971 Jan. 24 (Box 1)
    See also Whitney Museum of American Art
  - Arms, John Taylor, See National Academy of Design
  - Art Students League of New York, 1934 May 31; 1960 Mar.-Apr. (printed material) (Box 1)
  - Ball, Lucille, 1954 Feb. 12; 1954 Aug. 10,; 1955 Aug. 15,; 1956 June 4,; 1956 June 10 (outgoing carbon),; 1956 June 13,; 1956 Aug. 31 (outgoing carbon),; 1956 Sept. 5,; 1956 Sept. 11,; undated photograph of daughter, Lucie Arnaz (Box 1)
  - Baragrey, John, 1966 Aug. 25 (Box 1)
  - Barkley, Fred Alexander, 1935-1937 (printed material) (Box 1)
  - Beaufort Museum, 1970 Feb. 17; 1970 Mar. 20,; 1970 Mar. 24 (Box 1)
  - Beaux Arts Institute of Design, 1936 Oct. 19 (Box 1)
  - Bess, Forrest Clemenger, 1958 Dec. 31; 1962 May 31,; 1966 May 17,; 1966 July 25,; 1967 Jan. 4 (Box 1)
  - Birmingham Museum of Art, 1954 Feb. 5 (Box 1)
  - Bishop, Isabel, 1945 Nov. 12; 1954 Oct. 24,; 1962 Mar. 3,; 1971 Mar. 18,; undated (Box 1)
  - Blume, Peter and Ebie, 1955 Mar. 25; 1967 July 13,; 1970 Sept. 1,; 1970 Oct. 15 (Box 1)
    See also National Institute of Arts and Letters
  - Blumenthal, Joseph, 1965 June 2 (Box 1)
  - Broadcast Recording Service, 1960 Feb. 17 (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Gladys and Van Wyck, 1963 May 7 (printed material of Van Wyck's funeral); 1963 June 1,; undated (Box 1)
  - Cadmus, Paul, 1945 Nov. 7; 1960 Dec. 24,; 1963 Aug. 27,; 1966 Dec. 21,; 1969 June 17,; 1969 Dec. 29,; undated (photographs of Cadmus and his artwork) (Box 1)
  - Canaday, John, See The New York Times
  - Carnegie Institute. Department of Fine Arts, 1943 June 21; 1943 Dec. 11 (Box 1)
  - Cincinnati Art Museum, 1958 June 24; 1958 July 3,; 1958 (printed material) (Box 1)
  - Cunningham, Charles C., 1965 May 20; 1970 Oct. 20,; undated (Box 1)
    See also Wadsworth Atheneum
  - Custom Interiors, 1960 Dec. 12 (Box 1)
  - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1943 Feb. 27; undated (Box 1)
  - Dayton Art Institute, 1954 Apr. 19 (Box 1)
  - Downtown Gallery, 1963 June 4; 1965 July 6 (Box 1)
  - Eureka College, 1969 July 18; 1969 Dec. 9 (Box 1)
  - Fergusson, Erna, undated (Box 1)
  - Franklin, Frederic, undated (Box 1)
  - Freilich, Michael, See Roko Gallery
  - French, Jared, 1959 Dec. 20 (Box 1)
  - Galeria de Arte Mexicano, 1948 Apr. 23; 1949 May 25,; 1951 Apr. (photograph),; 1952 (photograph),; 1954 July 17,; 1954 Oct. 31 (outgoing carbon),; 1965 May 11 (Box 1)
  - Galloway, James, 1968 Aug. 28 (Box 1)
  - Gilbert, Edwin, 1966 Apr. 1 (Box 1)
  - Gollancz, Livia, 1965 Apr. 25; 1970 May 4 (Box 1)
  - Graham, Martha, 1967 Sept. 8 (Box 1)
  - Greenhood, David, 1958 Feb. 10 (Holiday House); 1968 Jan. 7,; 1968 Mar. 25,; 1969 Jan. 28,; 1970 Jan. 30,; 1970 Mar. 26,; 1970 July 5,; 1971 Feb. 25 (Box 1)
  - Hall, Ridgway M., See Beaufort Museum
  - Halpert, Edith Gregor, See Downtown Gallery
  - Museum of Fine Arts of Houston, 1960 Aug. 2 (outgoing carbon); 1960 Sept. 1 (Box 1)
  - Instituto Anglo-Mexicano de Cultura, 1954 Aug. 25 (Box 1)
  - Instituto Mexicano Norteamericano de Relaciones Culturales, 1954 Aug. 24 (Box 1)
  - Instituto Nacional de Bellas Artes, 1954 July 23 (Box 1)
  - Jackson, Charles, 1966 Jan. 19 (Box 1)
  - Jonson, Raymond, 1962 Mar. 5 (Box 1)
  - Juster Gallery, 1959 Nov. 15 (outgoing); 1959 Dec. 21 (photocopy from Jocelyn Ridgway Lehman),; 1960 Feb. 25 (carbon to WQXR) (Box 1)
  - Kerlan Collection, University of Minnesota, 1960 Feb. 26; undated; includes printed material (Box 1)
  - Kluckhohn, Clyde, 1951 July 29 (Box 1)
  - Koch, John, 1966 Nov. 29 (Box 1)
  - C.W. Kraushaar Art Galleries, 1943 Dec. 23; 1947 Feb. 28,; 1951 Aug. 27,; 1955 July 14,; 1959 May 29 (Box 1)
  - Laning, Edward, 1958 (printed material); undated (Box 1)
  - Lehman, Jocelyn Ridgway, 1959 Jan. 30 (carbon to Herbert P. Lansdale); 1959 Jan. 30 (carbon to Voice of America),; 1959 Dec. 21 (to Juster Gallery) (Box 1)
  - Levine, Jack, 1967 Jan. 10 (Box 1)
  - Library of Congress, 1937 Sept. 10; 1957 (Box 1)
  - March, Florence Eldridge, 1956 (?) (Box 1)
  - Martin, Hugh, 1957 June 2; 1964 Apr. 28,; undated (Box 1)
  - Meiser, Edith, 1963 June 15 (Box 1)
  - Morse, Robert, 1959; includes photographs of Goff portrait (Box 1)
  - National Academy of Design, 1937 Apr. 13 (Box 1)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1953 Dec. 24; 1958 Nov. 19 (Box 1)
  - Penitentiary of New Mexico, 1960 Aug. 15; 1960 Aug. 29 (Box 1)
  - The New York Herald Tribune, 1965 Jan. 14 (Box 1)
  - New York Public Library, 1947 Sept. 4 (Box 1)
  - The New York Times, 1959 Dec. 10; 1960 Mar. 14,; 1960 Nov. 16,; 1963 Nov. 6,; 1965 May 4,; 1966 Jan. 26 (Box 1)
  - Maron Palais Galleries, 1964 Apr. 21 (Box 1)
  - Papaconstantinou, Nicholas, See American Farm School
  - Parrish, Anne, 1949 July 9; 1957 Mar. 18 (Box 1)
  - Parsons, Betty, 1959 (photographs); 1963 Nov. 15 (Box 1)
  - Peters, Fritz, 1965 (photograph); 1966 Apr. 1,; 1966 Apr. 8,; 1966 Apr. 9,; 1966 Apr. 11,; 1966 May 18,; 1968 Jan. 24,; 1968 Jan. 28,; undated (photograph, printed material) (Box 1)
  - Pilates, Joseph Hubertus and Clara, 1957 Mar. 26; includes printed material (Box 1)
  - La Quinta Gallery, 1943 Feb. 20; 1954 Apr. 13,; 1955 Mar. 28 (Box 2)
  - Roko Gallery, 1966 Dec. 10 - 1967 Jan. 4 (printed material); 1967 Sept. 8 (outgoing carbon),; 1968 June 12 (Box 2)
  - Ruggles, Carl, undated; birthday address to his wife, Charlotte (Box 2)
  - Schnakenberg, Henry, 1967 Aug. 3; 1970 Jan. 2,; 1970 Apr. 12,; 1970 Apr. 15,; 1970 May? (Box 2)
  - Seale, Ervin, 1959 Nov. 10 (Box 2)
  - Shu, Ou Mie, 1968 (printed material - poetry); 1968 Sept. 18,; 1968 Oct. 22 (artwork); 1968 Oct. 26,; 1969 Apr. 1,; 1969 Sept. 23,; 1969 Oct. 27,; 1969 Nov. 22,; 1970 Sept. 10 (?),; 1971 Jan. 20,; 1971 Mar. 14 (Box 2)
  - Shubert, Katherine Schmidt, 1966 Feb. 6 (Box 2)
  - Simms, Albert G., See La Quinta Gallery
  - Sixtieth Street Gallery, 1935 Nov. 12 (Box 2)
  - Souza, Amilcar de, 1954 Apr. 21 (Box 2)
  - Springfield Art Museum, 1961 Mar. 28 (outgoing carbon) (Box 2)
  - Stamos, Theodoros, 1947 (photograph); 1948 May 31,; 1957,; undated (Box 2)
  - Thatcher, Madelaine, 1965 May 31 (Box 2)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1956 May 12 (Box 2)
  - Treasury Relief Art Project, See United States. Treasury Department
  - United Service Organizations for National Defense, 1942 July 17 (Box 2)
  - United States. Department of the Interior. Bureau of Reclamation, 1970 Feb. (printed material); 1971 Jan. 21 (Box 2)
  - United States. Federal Works Agency. Public Buildings Administration, See United States. Public Buildings Administration
  - United States. Office for Emergency Management, 1942 Feb. 18 (Box 2)
  - United States. Post Office, 1941 Aug. 19 (Box 2)
  - United States. Public Buildings Administration, 1939 Nov. 10; 1939 Dec. 5,; 1942 Mar. 14,; 1942 June 24,; 1943 Sept. 1,; 1943 Sept. 23,; 1968 Mar. (Box 2)
  - United States. Treasury Department, 1936 June 20; 1936 Oct. 10,; 1936 Oct. 16,; 1938 June 9 (Box 2)
  - Vance, Vivian, 1953 Oct. 20; 1954 Feb. 23,; 1955 Apr. 10,; 1955 Oct. 4,; 1955 Dec. 20,; 1956 Feb. 21 (outgoing holograph copy),; 1956 Mar. 2,; 1958 (photograph of Vance with Lucille Ball),; 1965 Feb. 24,; 1967 Sept. 3 (from Lauraine Delaney),; undated (Box 2)
  - Van Veen, Stuyvesant, undated (Box 2)
  - WQXR (radio stations), 1959 Dec. 9; 1960 Feb. 17 (interview),; 1960 Feb. 25 (photocopy from Juster Gallery) (Box 2)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1951 June 26 (Box 2)
  - Wardrop, James, 1954 Feb. 10 (Box 2)
  - Wescott, Glenway, 1948 Mar. 30; 1949 June 15,; 1960 Apr. 12,; 1960 May 31 (Box 2)
  - West Point Museum, 1960 Mar. 18; 1960 Apr. 12,; 1960 May 6,; 1961 Feb. 27,; 1961 May 25 (Box 2)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1937 Oct. 6; 1937 Nov. 17,; 1938 Apr. 11,; 1940 June 7,; 1941 Oct. 14,; 1951 Nov. 5,; 1954 Feb. 12,; 1954 Mar. 3 (Box 2)
  - Wickwire, Nancy, 1965 June 14 (Box 2)
  - Winans, Judith H., 1955 Sept. 15 (Box 2)
  - Writer's Digest, 1958 June 9 (Box 2)
  - Wyndham, Lee, 1962 Sept. 25 (Box 2)
  - Unidentified, 1 folder (Box 2)
- Artwork
  - Bookplates
    - Albuquerque Public Library (Box 3)
    - Albuquerque Public Library (original illustration) (Box 3)
  - Illustrations (book)
    - The Black Racer, dust jacket (Box 3)
    - Fly Redwing Fly, original (Box 3)
    - Fly Redwing Fly, production records (Box 3)
    - Golden Footlights, lithographs (Box 3)
    - New Mexico Quarterly, includes printed material from New Mexico Village Arts (Box 3)
    - New Mexico Village Arts, production records (Box 3)
    - New Mexico Village Arts, includes printed material (Box 3)
    - Red Man White Man, original (Box 3)
    - Run Sandpiper Run, original (Box 3)
    - Run Sandpiper Run, original (Oversize 1)
    - Run Sandpiper Run, production records (Box 3)
    - Sun in Your Eyes, original (Box 3)
  - Inventory of paintings (Box 3)
  - Juvenilia
    - Early drawings, paintings (Box 3)
  - Oil on canvas, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Pastel drawings, 1924-1937; undated; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Photographs
    - 1932-1959, 5 folders (Box 3)
    - 1960-1969, undated, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Reproductions (advertising)
    - Album covers - Gisele McKinsie (Box 4)
    - Ladies' Home Journal, Dec. 1955 (Box 4)
    - "The Lively Art of Living: Skyview on the Hudson" (Box 4)
    - Miscellany (Box 4)
  - Sketchbooks, "1925,"; "1928,"; "1932,"; "1937"; 4 folders (Box 4)
- Writings
  - Poetry - first poem - "The Northwest Wind", 1925 (Box 4)
  - Speeches - Pen and Brush Club, New York, 1967 May 9 (Box 4)
- Memorabilia
  - Exhibition list (Box 4)
  - Photographs
    - Family, 1905-1959; undated; 1 folder (Box 4)
    - Friends, 1939-1960; 1 folder (Box 4)
    - Goff, Lloyd Lózes
      - 1935-1951, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - 1952-1967, undated, 1 folder (Box 5)
    - Photographic button - Goff at age six months (Box 5)
  - Printed material
    - Articles, reviews, miscellany (Box 5)
    - Clippings, 1929-1971; undated; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Exhibition catalogs, announcements
      - Group shows, 1935-1968; undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
      - One-man shows, 1939-1971; undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Programs (theatrical), 1948; 1949 (Box 5)
    - Publicity for various books, 1948-1965; undated (Box 5)
  - Miscellany
    - Award - Boys' Clubs of America Junior Book Award for Run Sandpiper Run, 1958 (Box 5)
    - Identification cards, invitations, permits, receipts, personal documents (Box 5)